<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>se.sjoerd.GIScan</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <name>GIScan</name>
  <summary>Read and analyze GISAXS data stored in cbf format</summary>
  <developer_name>Sjoerd Broekhuijsen</developer_name>

  <description>
    <p>
      GIScan is a simple tool to open and analyze data stored in cbf (Crystallographic Binary Format) files. While
      GIScan is primarily developed with the analyis of GISAXS data in mind, as obtained by the P03 beamline of PETRA
      III at the DESY Synchrotron in Hamburg, Germany, it should be compatible with any arbitrary cbf data.
      </p>
    <p>
      GIScan handles raw data directly and doesn't need any a-priori data reduction. It supports features such as
      background subtraction, line scans along the Qy and Qz axis, detection of the full-width at half-maximum (FWHM)
      of diffraction peaks and coordinate conversion from pixels to reciprocal or angular space. </p>
    <p>
      GIScan is mostly developed with the analysis of multilayers in mind but can be used for any arbitrary data stored
      in cbf format. If a beamline or datatype (be it GISAXS or GISANS) is not supported and you would like to use this
      tool, please submit an issue on the Github page so this can be arranged.
    </p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">se.sjoerd.GIScan.desktop</launchable>

  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/SjoerdB93/GIScan/issues</url>
  <url type="help">https://github.com/SjoerdB93/GIScan/</url>
  <url type="homepage">https://www.sjoerd.se</url>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>GIScan main view</caption>
      <image>http://www.sjoerd.se/giscan_main.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>GIScan settings</caption>
      <image>http://www.sjoerd.se/giscan_settings.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    
     <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>GIScan settings</caption>
      <image>http://www.sjoerd.se/giscan_vert.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    
    
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>GIScan background substraction</caption>
      <image>http://www.sjoerd.se/giscan_bg.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  
  <releases>
  
    <release version="1.1.5" date="2022-12-13">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Updated Flatpak runtime</li>
          <li>Added symbolic icon</li>          
          <li>Updated icons to vector image</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    
     <release version="1.1.4" date="2022-12-12">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Expanded permissions to home folder for Flatpak version</li>
          <li>Update screenshots on Flathub</li>              
          <li>Use native filechooser</li>    
          <li>Minor bug fixes and code cleanup</li>                    
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    
     <release version="1.1.3" date="2022-10-07">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed a bug where ROI selection didn't work properly if last sample ended on background selection</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    
        <release version="1.1.2" date="2022-09-21">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Added grids to the scan graphs</li>
          <li>Added an option for dark graphs to facilitate dark mode themes</li>
          <li>Minor bug fixes</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  
    <release version="1.1.1" date="2022-09-19">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed a bug where ROI and Background rectangles didn't switch properly after using FWHM scan function</li>
          <li>FWHM scan settings are now persistent over usage</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    
    <release version="1.1.0" date="2022-09-16">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Implemented a FWHM scan function to scan FWHM of Bragg sheet in Qz space over different positions in Qy (still in Beta)</li>
          <li>Future updates in short term will mostly focus on improving this functionality</li>
          <li>Made minor UI chances to ensure compatibility with smaller screen resolutions</li>
          <li>Added a few general bug fixes to prevent GIScan from crashing unexpectedly</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    
    <release version="1.0.1" date="2022-09-12">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Changed the coordinates to grid-layout to save space</li>
          <li>Changed rounding in entry to 4 digits</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="1.0.0" date="2022-09-10">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Initial release</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  
  <recommends>
  <control>keyboard</control>
  <control>pointing</control>
</recommends>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

</component>
